Hello English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today
we're bringing you the
next part of our suspense
series the new guy
in town. That's right.
So we know that
Armonda wasn't really a
vampire that he was
just acting and the women
aren't quite what they
see in this dialogue.
In the last one something
happened as she transformed
into some sort of, I don't
know, creature, right?
Monster, right? So now
let's see what happened.
So we're not going to preview
any vocabulary this time.
Let's just listen to the
dialogue and see what happens.
What the heck is going
on? Did you see that?
What was that thing? I don't
know. I'm just how we made it out.
Look, there's a police star.
Help! Help! Please, please stop!
How do you man? What
seems to be the problem?
Is this man bothering
your officer?
Officer, there is like a
witch creature back there.
We tied her up, but she broke me
and she was about to have us for dinner.
Okay, calm down, calm down.
Let me see your eyes,
please. Have you been
drinking tonight, son?
We're telling the truth.
She's in there. We suspected
her being a kidnapper
or a rapist, but it turns
out she's an alien or
something. Okay,
calm down, calm down.
Let me see your eyes, please. Seriously,
are you going to help us out or not?
Okay, let's go have
a look, shall we?
Hello? Is anyone in there?
Be careful. She might be hiding.
That's perfectly safe. There isn't anyone.
[Music]
Well, I don't think things are turning out
very well for our housewives and our minds.
Apparently, the police officer is not
going to make it to the next episode.
All right, so we saw some
really great vocabulary
and even though it's kind of a scary story,
there is a lot of things we can learn.
So why don't we take a look
at it now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Well, we're going to look at
five words and phrases
here. And the first one,
they described this woman as a
kind of creature. Creature. Creature.
All right, so what exactly is a creature?
Well, a creature can be any animal.
Any animal. Yeah, like
from a mouse to a bird to
an insect or a bug. So I can
say a bird is a flying creature.
Exactly. All right,
but sometimes we
also use it to mean an
unknown and scary animal.
So there's a creature under my bed. Yes,
or some type of creature was attacking me.
Okay, so a creature can be
any sort of living thing or animal.
All right, what
about our next one?
Well, the creature broke
free from some ropes.
All right, so to
break free, break free.
And what does that
mean? When you break free,
you escape from something
that stops you moving.
Okay, so you have the
ability to move again.
Yes, you break free from
maybe ropes or chains
or even a relationship.
Okay, so I can say, oh, I
finally broke free from
that awful relationship.
Now, that's quite interesting
the way we can use
this in different ways. So
why don't we take a look
at some examples now? Example one. We tied
up the dog, but he is trying to break free.
Example two. I'm glad that I broke
free from that horrible relationship.
Example three. I want to break
free from all my daily responsibilities.
Okay, so break free.
It's clear now. Mm-hmm.
So why don't we move
on to our next word?
They thought that
maybe this creature was a
kidnapper, kidnapper, kidnapper.
Okay, so this is a criminal.
So a kidnapper
is a criminal. Yep.
All right, and what exactly
does a kidnapper do?
a kidnapper takes someone
to a place and keeps
them there against
their will against their will
with force or violence.
All right, so so I guess
that makes sense, right?
Because the word has kidding.
It's yep. So to take children.
Yes, but it can be also
you can kidnap an adult.
Yes, that's true. All
right. So this word
can actually be used
in three different ways.
So we saw a kidnapper,
right? Okay, that is the person.
Yeah, and the verb to
kidnap. Okay, or a noun
describing an action
kidnapping. A kidnapping.
So yeah, a kidnapping took
place today. Okay, so very
interesting word. And of course
it's illegal to be a kidnapper.
Yes. So our next
word is also very
serious and it's also a
crime, right? That's right.
A rapist. A rapist. A
rapist. Okay, so that is
a person that who forces
someone to have sex.
Okay, so again against
their will. Right, a kidnapper.
Exactly. Okay, and the
verb would be too rape too
rape to rape someone.
Okay, so on the lighter side,
we heard the police officers say
something in a very strange way.
He said, let me see
your eyes, please.
Okay, so this is an
interesting phrase.
It's it's a sound made from
pushing two words together, right?
So let me why don't
we hear a few more
examples of this and see if
we can figure out what are
the two words. Example one. Let me
have a look inside the car. Example two.
Let me go out tonight,
dad. Please. Example three.
Let me think about it
and I'll give you an answer
tomorrow. So basically,
let me is let me let me.
Yeah, let me have that
pen. Okay, let me see.
Now we do this also
with other words, right?
Yeah, another example
would be gimme gimme.
Yeah, so that is
give me exactly.
Okay, so an interesting thing,
it's not proper English, right?
No, you wouldn't really
write it this way, but
find it in the dictionary,
but it's really common
when people speak. And
actually, it's more likely
that you'll say, let me
give me then let me give
me. Okay, very good.
So I think now it's time for
us to listen to our dialogue
for the second time.
And then we'll come back and look at some
other phrases that we saw in our dialogue.
What the heck is going on? Did you see
that? What was that thing? I don't know.
I'm just glad we made it out. Look, there's
a police car. Help, help. Please stop.
Howdy, man. What seems to be the problem?
Is this man bothering you? Officer.
Officer, there is like a
witch creature back there.
We tied her up,
but she broke free,
and she was about to have us for dinner.
Okay, calm down, calm down.
Let me see your eyes, please.
Have you been drinking tonight, son?
We are telling the
truth. She's in there.
We suspected her of
being a kidnapper or rapist,
but it turns out she's
an alien or something.
Okay, calm down, calm
down. Let me see your eyes,
please. Oh, seriously, are
you going to help us or not?
Okay, let's go have
a look, shall we?
Hello? Is anyone in here?
Be careful. She might be hiding.
It's perfectly safe. There isn't anyone.
We're going to look at two phrases
now in Fluency Builder that you might hear
when you're talking about
a crime. Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase that
we're going to look at
is what the heck is going on? What the heck
is going on? What the heck is going on?
Okay, so this is just asking
what's happening, right?
Right, but it's a very
strong way of saying
what's happening. Yeah,
what really is happening?
Uh-huh. Now, why do
they say what the heck?
What is heck? Well, heck is
sort of a polite way of saying hell.
Okay, so instead of saying what the
hell is going on, what the heck is going
on? Now, and why do
you do this? Um, because in
especially in American English, uh, we
don't like to talk about religious words.
So like, hell and God and
Jesus, these things are, um,
impolite and American. Right,
you don't want to offend anyone.
Right. So that's why we would have other
words like, oh my gosh. For, oh my God.
Or Jeez. Instead
of Jesus. Right.
Okay, so that is an interesting
thing. And of course,
it's, it is a little bit of a sensitive
topic among some people.
So that's why it's better to just use
these synonyms. Yes. Okay. And what about
her next phrase? So they
suspected her of being a kidnapper.
Okay. So suspected her of being a
kidnapper. Yeah, suspect someone of being
something. So I
suspect she is an alien.
Right. I suspect him
of being a liar. Okay. So
what about to suspect?
What does that mean exactly?
She thinks something
that is true, but not
be a hundred percent
sure. So you can say, I
think she is a kidnapper.
Yep. Oh, I suspect
her of being a kidnapper.
Hmm. Interesting.
Why don't we hear a few
more examples? Example one.
The police suspected him
of being a bank robber.
Example two. We suspect our
dog is responsible for this mess.
Example three.
The neighborhood suspected
that our neighbor was selling drugs.
All right. Very good. So
we've seen a lot of vocab.
We've seen these
phrases. So I think it's time
for us to listen to our
dialogue for the last time.
And then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
What the heck is going on? Did you see
that? What was that thing? I don't know.
I'm just how we made it
up. Look, there's a police car.
Help. Help. Please, please stop.
How do you ma'am? What
seems to be the problem?
Is this man bothering
your officer?
Officer, there is like a
witch creature back there.
We tied her up,
but she broke me.
And she was about
to have us for dinner.
Okay, calm down, calm down.
Let me see your eyes, please.
Have you been drinking tonight,
son? We're telling the truth.
She's in there. We suspected her
being a kidnapper or a
rapist, but turns out she's
an alien or something.
Okay, calm down. Calm down.
Let me see your eyes, please.
Seriously? Are you going to
help us out or not? Okay,
let's go have a look, shall we?
Hello? Is anyone in there?
Be careful. She might be hiding.
It's perfectly safe. There isn't anyone.
Okay, well, Marco, we're
coming near the end of
this series, aren't
we? Yes, exactly.
It's a short series, but what
do you think happens or how do
you think the series ends?
What is really going on?
A mystery here at English Pods,
so we want you to hear from you.
What do you think
is going to happen?
Exactly. Come to our
website at englishpot.
com where you can leave us
your questions, your comments,
or even maybe your ideas,
not only for this lesson,
but for any lesson that
you would like to hear.
That's right. Well, guys,
we're happy that you
downloaded this lesson,
and remember to check out
our website. But until next time,
thanks for listening, and goodbye.